Yuan LYU

Product | Interaction | UX Design

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction and Design Double Degree

Technical University Berlin, Germany *Oct.2016 ~ Present* University Paris-Sud, France *Sep.2015 ~ Jun.2016*

Minor Innovation and Entrepreneurship

EIT Digital Master School Sep. 2015 ~ Present

Bachelor of Engineering in Network Engineering

Dalian Maritime University, China Sep.2011 ~ Jun.2015

EXPERIENCE

Product Support Working Student, Jovoto GmbH.
 Product Team, Berlin, Germany Mar. 2017 ~ May. 2017

Create user flows and wireframes for products concept papers Technically translate internal as well as external bug reports Validate and enrich bug reports with all needed information

UI/UX Designer, Bingo for elders

Quality and Usability Project Oct.2016 ~ Mar.2017

In charge of UI Design and User test for this Android tablet game.

APP Designer & Technical Support, Transmetics

Business Development Lab Course Sep. 2015 ~ Sep. 2016

Run a project as a start-up, in charge of APP Design, Android platform development, user test and market analysis.

UX Intern, FOTILE Kitchen Ware Co. Ltd.

Innovation Institute, Oct.2014 ~ Jan.2015

Co-designed interface for new oven, steam box and microwave oven Implement the high-fidelity Prototype

Made reasonable user test script, participated in user test

Research Assistant, Sino-European Usability Center (SEUC)
Dalian Maritime University, Nov. 2013 ~ Jun. 2015

Research on Dining-out of Chinese Youth and Innovation Opportunities with NCR (National Cash Register)

Corporation Designed questionnaire, did user interviews and gathered feedbacks by following the UCD method

Research on Service Design of College Community Website

Analyzed requirements and competitive, made the interface model and did relevant programming

- **4** +49(0)157-3326-2956
- yuan.lyu@hotmail.com
- http://cocoyuan.github.io
- Berlin, Germany 10963

PROFILE

As a hybrid designer with programming experiences, I am adept at understanding of user story, and always have the passion to use my creativity to solve unusual problems and design for uncommon digital products.

Sincerely look forward to an internship in the area of Product, Interaction and UX Design.

SKILLS

DESIGN

In-Depth Interview
Questionnaire
Persona | Scenario
Conceptual Storyboard
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Test
Sketch/Photoshop
Axture/InVision
Balsamiq/OmniGraffle

PROGRAMMING

JAVA/C#
HTML/CSS
ASP.NET
SQL Server/MySQL
JavaScript
Arduino
Node.js

LANGUAGE

Chinese: Native English: Fluent Italian: Beginner